Guide to the Keller Lectures collection ARCH075
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
- Recordings, 1958-1976; IV
  - The United States, France, and the Future of Europe; Stanley H. Hoffmann, 1965 Jan 7; 3 Reels (Box Audio Reels 3)
  - A Symposium on Interpersonal Relations, 1965 Dec 1; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 3)
    This is a recording of a faculty symposium held at the beginning of the Keller Lecture's eighth season. Participants included George M. Evica, Malthon Anapol, William Brayfield, and John Margerones.
  - Language is More than Words; Henry Lee Smith, Jr., 1965 Dec 2; 11 Reels (Box Audio Reels 3)
  - Informal Student Seminar with Henry Lee Smith, Jr., 1965 Dec 3; 3 Reels (Box Audio Reels 3)
  - GAMES: Theoretical Experiments in Conflict and Cooperation; Anatol Rapoport, 1965 Dec 7; 6 Reels One set of three reels, a set of two reels, and a single reel of an incomplete set. (Box Audio Reels 3)
  - Informal Student Seminar with Anatol Rapoport, 1965 Dec 8; 2 Reels Two duplicate copies (Box Audio Reels 3)
  - Informal Student Seminar of All University Symposium - "Literary Personal and Social Quests;" Edwin Moseley, 1965 Dec 10; 2 Reels (Box Audio Reels 3)
  - Public Opinion and the Relations Between Nations; Ithiel De Sola Pool, 1965 Dec 13; 7 Reels Three pairs of duplicates, and a version on one reel. (Box Audio Reels 3, Box Audio Reels 4)
  - Informal Student Seminar with Ithiel De Sola Pool, 1965 Dec 15; 2 Reels Parts 1 and 2 (Box Audio Reels 4)
  - University of Hartford's Faculty Women's Club honors Mrs. Alexander S. Keller at a special luncheon, 1966 May 7; 6 Reels One reel (arch075av00146) is labelled "Grattan at Dinner for Keller" (Box Audio Reels 4, Box Audio Reels 7)
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Two versions of the recording exist. One version is split across three reels (arch075av0061-arch075av0063) and another is on two sides of one reel (arch075av0146). Both versions were digitized. While the version from three reels may sound better in spots, it is missing 17 seconds from Carolyn Keller's speech on the third reel. Therefore, the one-reel version is the one that is publically available. To access the other version, contact archives@hartford.edu.
  - Keller Preview of University of Hartford China Talks, 1966 Dec 1; 2 Reels (Box Audio Reels 4)
    According to press releases in the collection, this event was a preview of the forthcoming Keller lectures on China that occured on Dec. 12-15. This event was to include talks from University of Hartford Professors: Albert F. Hamel, Eugene T. Sweeney, and Ivan Galantic.
  - The Nature of Chinese Power in Asia, 1966 Dec 12; 6 Reels (Box Audio Reels 4)
    The recording is of the roundtable discussion entitled, "The Nature of Chinese Power in Asia," which featured Harrison E. Salisbury, as the moderator, and Harold Jacobson [who replaced Robert W. Barnett], Edwin Reischauer, Harold Isaacs, and Donald Zagoria as the participants. The discussion was broadcast on WHNB-TV, Channel 30, live from WHNB-TV studios.
  - China in Asia; Edwin Reischauer, 1966 Dec 12; 12 Reels (Box Audio Reels 4)
  - Chinese Civilization and its Legacy; Arthur F. Wright, 1966 Dec 13; 3 Reels (Box Audio Reels 4)
  - Cultural and Educational Developments in Red China (PM discussion); C.T. Hu, 1966 Dec 13; 3 Reels (Box Audio Reels 4)
  - The Chinese Cultural Revolution and the Red Guards; Jonathan Spence, 1966 Dec 13; 2 Reels The audio reels share with recordings of Frederick Nossal and Giri Deshingkar on the other sides. (Box Audio Reels 4)
  - Recent Report from China; Frederick Nossal, 1966 Dec 13; 1 Reels The other side of the audio reel is one of Jonathan Spence's recordings. (Box Audio Reels 4)
  - Concepts of Chinese Power in Asia; Gordon Berger, 1966 Dec 13; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 5)
  - Our Relations with China: Images and Realities; Harold Isaacs, 1966 Dec 13; 9 Reels (Box Audio Reels 5)
  - Reflections on Our China Policy; James C. Thomson, 1966 Dec 14; 3 Reels (Box Audio Reels 5)
  - China as a World Power (AM discussion); Giri D. Deshingkar, 1966 Dec 14; 1 Reels has a recording of Jonathan Spence on the other side. 7 inch (Box Audio Reels 4)
  - China as a World Power (PM discussion); Giri D. Deshingkar, 1966 Dec 14; 2 Reels Recording is on one reel, second reel is a duplicate 7 inch (Box Audio Reels 5)
  - China's Military Potential; Frank Armbruster, 1966 Dec 14; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 5)
  - Modern Taiwan; Myron Cohen, 1966 Dec 14; 3 Reels (Box Audio Reels 5)
  - Economic Problems of Red China, (AM discussion); Carl Riskin, 1966 Dec 14; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 5)
  - Economic Problems of Red China, (PM discussion); Carl Riskin, 1966 Dec 14; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 5)
  - Land Reform [AM and PM?]; Roy Hofheinz, 1966 Dec 14; 2 Reels Labelled Tape #1 and Tape #2, but also as Part II and Part III.; 1 Reels May contain both morning and afternoon sessions (Box Audio Reels 5)
  - Marxism in Red China; Mark Selden, 1966 Dec 14; 3 Reels (Box Audio Reels 5)
  - Moscow-Peking-Hanoi: The War in Viet Nam; Donald S. Zagoria, 1966 Dec 14; 10 Reels (Box Audio Reels 5)
  - China Faces West; Edgar Snow, 1967 Mar 22; 5 Reels (Box Audio Reels 5, Box Audio Reels 6)
  - Racial Crisis in Perspective; Gunnar Myrdal, 1968 Mar 12; 9 Reels Three duplicate sets of the lecture. Two sets of three reels, and one set of two reels. Plus one copy on within a set of 4 reels of all 1968 lectures. (Box Audio Reels 6)
  - Student forum with Gunnar Myrdal, 1968 Mar 13; 2 Reels; 2 Reels Part of 2 reels (one side on each) within a set of 4 reels of all 1968 lectures. (Box Audio Reels 6)
  - Race and Reality; Alvin F. Poussaint, 1968 Mar 18; 3 Reels; 2 Reels Part of 2 reels (one side of each) within a set of 4 reels of all March 1968 lectures. (Box Audio Reels 6)
  - Student Forum with Alvin F. Poussaint, 1968 Mar 19; 2 Reels; 1 Reels reel includes Wilson's lecture from March 25 (Box Audio Reels 6)
  - Community Versus City: The New Era in Urban Problems; James Quinn Wilson, 1968 Mar 25; 5 Reels; 1 Reels reel includes Poussaint's March 19 forum; 1 Reels reel includes Wilson's forum on March 26. (Box Audio Reels 6)
  - Student Forum with James Quinn Wilson, 1968 Mar 26; 2 Reels; 1 Reels reel includes Wilson's March 25 lecture. (Box Audio Reels 6)
  - A Sense of the Past; Robert Penn Warren, 1969 Feb 11; 2 Reels (Box Audio Reels 6)
  - Discussion with Students in Suisman Lounge with Robert Penn Warren, 1969 Feb 12; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 6)
  - Technology and Imagination; Donald Hall, 1969 Mar 5; 2 Reels 7 inches; 1 Reels 5 inches (Box Audio Reels 6, Box Audio Reels 7)
  - Address to Students and Faculty in Suisman Lounge; Donald Hall, 1969 Mar 6; 2 Reels (Box Audio Reels 7)
  - Gallery talk by Theodore Gunn, 1970 Mar 3; 1 Reels 7 inch; 1 Reels 5 inch (Box Audio Reels 7)
  - Crime and the International Context; Sir Leon Radzinowicz, 1971 Mar 16; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 7)
  - Crime, Fear and Law Enforcement; Abraham S. Goldstein, 1971 Mar 18; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 7)
  - Legal Protection Against Crime Control Systems; Alan F. Westin, 1971 Mar 25; 2 Reels (Box Audio Reels 7)
    General
    This recording was rebroadcast by WTIC on April 1, 1971 (which is why the reels are marked with this date, rather than the date the lecture was recorded.).
  - Panel Discussion, 1971 Mar 26; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 7)
    The March 26, 1971 panel discussed Alan Westin's lecture. Panelists included Alan Westin, State Senator Jay W. Jackson, Captain Wayne H. Bishop of the State Police, and Attorney Alvin Pudlin who was a cooperating attorney with the Connecticut Civil Liberties Union.
  - The Film Maker Discusses Some Recent Works; Standish Lawder, 1972 Mar 13; 1 Reels Side I of a reel (Side II has first part of Youngblood recording) (Box Audio Reels 7)
  - The Cinema as Environment; Gene Youngblood, 1972 Mar 15; 2 Reels Recording is split into two reels, Youngblood is on sides "II and III." The other sides of these reels are the Lawder, Renan, and O'Grady recordings. (Box Audio Reels 7)
  - The West Coast Independent Film and the Growth of Man; Sheldon Renan, 1972 Mar 20; 1 Reels Is side IV (the recordings for this season are on three reels) (Box Audio Reels 7)
  - Autobiography in the New American Cinema; Gerald O'Grady, 1972 Mar 22; 2 Reels Sides IV and V (This season is split across three reels) (Box Audio Reels 7)
  - The New Foreign Policy of the United States; Hans J. Morgenthau, 1973 Oct 31; 3 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 1)
  - Student Discussion with Hans J. Morgenthau, 1973 Nov 1; 2 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 1)
  - The United States and Western Europe; Stanley H. Hoffmann, 1974 Apr 18; 4 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 1)
  - The United States on the Eve of the Bicentennial, Lecture 1; Alvin F. Poussaint, 1975 Mar 19; 6 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 1)
  - The United States on the Eve of the Bicentennial, Lecture 2; Alvin F. Poussaint, 1975 Mar 20; 6 Cassettes (Box Cassette Box 1)
  - Art Collecting as a Social Habit; Joseph Alsop, 1976 Oct 27; 4 Reels (Box Audio Reels 7)
  - Dr. Yosha announces the Keller Lecture Series, undated; 1 Reels 5 inch reel (Box Audio Reels 7)
  - Dr. Yosha opens the Keller Lecture Series, undated; 1 Reels 5 inch reel (Box Audio Reels 7)
  - End of unidentified lecture, undated; 1 Reels (Box Audio Reels 7)
- Duplicates, 1958-1975; V (Box 4, Folder 16-22, Box 5, Folder 1-20)
  This series consists of duplicate documents and photographs found throughout the collection. The majority of the duplicates are programs and transcripts from Series I: Lecture Seasons.